A Guide to the Virginia Auditor of Public Accounts - Allowances: Lists of Claims, 1809-1865
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Virginia Auditor of Public Accounts - Allowances: Lists of Claims, 1809-1865
The Library of Virginia
APA 153
2.7 cu. ft. (6 boxes)
Virginia. Auditor of Public Accounts (1776-1928)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Auditor of Public Accounts in 1913.
Biographical Information
On 2 December 1793 the General Assembly passed an act requiring that the money derived from militia fines be deposited in the treasury and used to pay officers' salaries and purchase equipment for the militia.
Scope and Content
This series consists of lists of claims against the militia fine fund, 1809-1865, that were allowed by regimental courts. Each list contains the names of the claimants, the amounts claimed, the regimental number and county, and the purposes of the expenditures. The series is arranged chronologically and by militia regiment within years.
Claims include payments for attending as provost martial or adjutant, payments to drummers and fifers, attendance to courts of inquiry or training, and payments to clerks, among others.
These records are part of Auditor of Public Accounts. Administration of State Government: Funds - Militia Fine Fund.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Allowances, 1809 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Allowances, 1816 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Allowances, 1817 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Allowances, 1821 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Allowances, 1st-28th Regiment, 1823 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Allowances, 30th-59th Regiment, 1823 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Allowances, 60th-79th Regiment, 1823 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Allowances, 80th-99th Regiment, 1823 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Allowances, 100th-128th Regiment, 1823 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Allowances, 1st-29th Regiment, 1825 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Allowances, 30th-59th Regiment, 1825 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Allowances, 60th-89th Regiment, 1825 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Allowances, 90th-110th Regiment, 1825 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Allowances, 111th-130th Regiment, 1825 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Allowances, 1st-29th Regiment, 1829 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Allowances, 30-59th Regiment, 1829 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Allowances, 60th-79th Regiment, 1829 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Allowances, 80th-109th Regiment, 1829 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Allowances, 113th-132nd Regiment, 1829 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Allowances, 1st-29th Regiment, 1832 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Allowances, 30th-59th Regiment, 1832 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Allowances, 61st-99th Regiment, 1832 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Allowances, 100th-140th Regiment, 1832 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Allowances, 1st-19th Regiment 1839 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Allowances, 20th-39th Regiment, 1839 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Allowances, 40th-69th Regiment, 1839 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Allowances, 70th-89th Regiment, 1839 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Allowances, 90th-119th Regiment, 1839 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Allowances, 120th-139th Regiment, 1839 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Allowances, 140-156th Regiment, 1839 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Allowances, 1847 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Allowances, 1st-29th Regiment, 1848 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Allowances, 30th-59th Regiment, 1848 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Allowances, 60th-79th Regiment, 1848 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Allowances, 80th-99th Regiment, 1848 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Allowances, 100th-129th Regiment, 1848 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Allowances, 130th-159th Regiment, 1848 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Allowances, 160th-180th Regiment, 1848 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Allowances, 1849 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Allowances, 1859-1860 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Allowances, 1st-49th Regiment, 1861 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Allowances, 52nd-98th Regiment, 1861 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Allowances, 102-133rd Regiment, 1861 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Allowances, 144th-198th Regiment, 1861 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Allowances, 4th-129th Regiment, 1862-1863 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Allowances, 133rd-192nd Regiment, 1862-1863 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Allowances, 1864-1865 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Allowances, Unpaid claims, 1858-1862 (Box 6, Folder 7)